Emmanuel CHARON

emmanuel.charon@outlook.com +33 6 80 92 91 05

I am a battle-proven Machine Learning programmer with experience in a startup environment.

Areas of expertise: machine learning, cloud computing, backend dev, game design, product design, dev Unity.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2015 - Present *Entrepreneur*, Paris, France.

- Founded Irminsul Studio: development and distribution of video games.
- Designed a product for audit companies.

Apr 2013 - Jun 2015 Diffbot Corp. Inc, Palo Alto, California, USA. (Startup with <= 10 employees)

Machine Learning Engineer. Built an artificial intelligence to analyze web pages and

extract relevant data:

- Designed, coded, tested, and improved state-of-the-art AI algorithms to

automatically extract structured data from web pages.

- Lead a product release (API) as a team and project manager.

- Also conducted technical hiring, live operations, business strategy, and prototype

development.

Sept 2012 - Mar 2012 Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.

Teaching assistant for the classes "Introduction to computer networks" and "Internet

routing protocols and standards".

Jun 2012 - Aug 2012 *Cisco Systems*, San Jose, California, USA.

Designed and coded a generic consistency verifier for the Nexus 7000, a cutting-edge

datacenter technology.

Apr 2011 - Jul 2011 *TelecomParisTech/LINCS*, Paris, France:

Research internship on networks and congestion control. "Prix du Stage de

recherche" (Prize of the research internship) awarded by the Ecole Polytechnique for

outstanding work and results.

Sept 2008 - Apr 2009 *Gendarmerie Nationale* (French National Police), Caen, France.

Eight-month leadership training, a part of the Ecole Polytechnique curriculum. Worked

in an Intelligence Agency.

EDUCATION

Sept 2011 - April 2013 Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA.

Master's of Science in Electrical Engineering awarded in April 2013. Intensive

coursework on computer networks, data analysis and machine learning. GPA: 4/4.

Sept 2008 - Sept 2011 *Ecole Polytechnique*, Paris, France.

France's leading university for high-level scientific training. "Diplôme d'ingénieur" and

"Diplôme de l'Ecole Polytechnique" awarded with a specialization in electrical

engineering.

Interdisciplinary research project on exoplanet discoveries (Sept 2009 - June 2010).

LANGUAGES AND COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: French (native language), English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate).

Programming languages: Java, Python, C#, JavaScript/HTML/CSS, C, C++, PHP, Matlab.